A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Latin America and the Caribbean Program, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil Field Office, Office Files of Shepard Forman FA630
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Latin America and the Caribbean Program, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil Field Office, Office Files of Shepard Forman
1977-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA630
1.2 Cubic Feet
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of Chronological Files and correspondence to and from Shepard Forman. The Chronological Files are mainly comprised of letters from organizations or individuals soliciting grant funds, proposals, and letters to grantees requesting supplementary information, etc.
Biographical / Historical
In July 1977, Shepard Forman became the Program Advisor/Program Specialist at the Rio de Janeiro - Brazil Office; one of several overseas offices within the Ford Foundation’s Latin America and the Caribbean Program. In August 1980, Forman became the Program Officer of the Brazil Office. The goals and objectives of the Overseas Development Program guided the work of all overseas offices. Overseas Development Program assistance supported educational, training, and research institutions and activities essential to the social, economic, and educational advancement of developing nations in Latin America and the Caribbean as well as in South and Southeast Asia, the Near East, and Africa.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in chronological order.
Conditions Governing Access
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Chronological Files and Correspondence, 1977-1980; I
  - Chron File October 2, 1979 - December 27, 1979, 1979 October 2 - December 27 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366))
  - Chron File June 1, 1979 – September 26, 1979, 1979 June 1 – September 26 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 2)
  - Chron File April 2, 1979 – May 31, 1979, 1979 April 2 – May 31 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 3)
  - Chron File January 1979 – March 1979, 1979 January – March (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 4)
  - Chron File August 1, 1978, 1978 August 1 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 5)
  - Chron File May 3, 1978 – July 26, 1978, 1978 May 3 – July 26 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 6)
  - Chron File January 2, 1978 – April 28, 1978, 1978 January 2 – April 28 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 7)
  - Chron File August 15, 1977 – December 29, 1977, 1977 August 15 – December 29 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 8)
  - Chron copies August 12, 1977 – November 11, 1977, 1977 August 12 – November 11 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 9)
  - Chron copies November 17, 1977 – December 29, 1977, 1977 November 17 – December 29 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 10)
  - Correspondence to/from S. Forman January 3, 1978 – February 27, 1978, 1978 January 3 – February 27 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 11)
  - (memos – internal) Correspondence – external August 14, 1978 – December 29, 1978, 1978 August 14 – December 29 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 12)
  - Chron IV March – April 1978, 1978 March – April (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 13)
  - Correspondence to/from April 21, 1978 – July 25, 1978, 1978 April 21 – July 25 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 14)
  - Chron File January 1979 – March 1979, 1979 January – March (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 15)
  - Chron copies April 2, 1979 – May 31, 1979, 1979 April 2 – May 31 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 16)
  - Chron File June 1, 1979 – September 26, 1979, 1979 June 1 – September 26 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 17)
  - Chron File October 2, 1979 – December 27, 1979, 1979 October 2 – December 27 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 18)
  - Chron File January 4, 1980 – March 31, 1980, 1980 January 4 – March 31 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 19)
  - Chron File April 1980 – July 14, 1980, 1980 April – July 14 (Box 1 (#7280; SK #36366), Folder 20)